Marine, this hearing falls under
the jurisdiction of the United Nations.
士兵，本次听证会由联合国授权
Now, you understand this is a deposition,
not a trial.
你要明白，这是判决，不是审讯
The charges against you are serious.
Desertion of your post. Dereliction of duty.
你的指控很严重，擅离职守和失职
Any legal actions that may
or may not proceed from this investigation
任何可能采取的法律行为将以本次调查为依据
will be adjudicated under
the Uniform Code of Military Justice.
由军事审判统一法规裁定
Do you understand your rights
in this matter?
你清楚你在本次事件中的权利吗？
Yes, sir.
是的，先生
Lieutenant Abramowitz.
Abramowitz中尉
Sergeant Brandon Beckett,
Brandon Beckett中士
please can you tell us where you were
on the 4th ofAugust, 2010?
告诉我们，2010年8月4日，你在什么地方？
The Democratic Republic of the Congo
in Africa.
在非洲，刚果民主共和国
What were you doing in Africa?
你在非洲做什么？
My squad had just transferred
from Kabul, Afghanistan two months earlier.
我的小队两个月前从阿富汗喀布尔调动过去
Your assignment?
你们的任务？
We were there as part of ATEP.
我们是ATEP的成员
The Africa Train and Equip Program.
非洲训练和装备计划
We were helping train
the Congolese regular army
我们帮助训练刚果正规军
to resist the incursion of well-armed
rebel forces backed by terrorist groups.
对抗装备精良的叛军侵略，叛军幕后有恐怖组织
In exchange, African troops would join
the coalition forces in Afghanistan.
作为交换条件，非洲军队会加入在阿富汗的联军
Can you describe the events that led
to you going AWOL eight days later?
请详细讲一下导致你八天后擅离职守的事件
It started August 3rd at the parade ground...
那是八月三日，在阅兵场……
The AKS-74, the Soviet weapon
designed to replace the AK-47.
AKS-74，被设计来取代AK-47的苏制武器
Most likely, this or one of its variants
is what your enemy will be using.
你们的敌人大部分都使用它或它的改进版
The rifle is chambered
for the 5.45 x 39mm round,
这种步枪使用5.45×39mm子弹
similar to our 5.56mm NATO round.
和北约的5.56mm子弹相似
Only the AKS uses a 52-grain steel-core
bullet, designed to penetrate body armor.
而只有AKS使用52格令钢芯子弹，可以射穿敌人的护甲
（1格令=0.0648克）
This weapon's barrel
has a one in eight twist.
这种武器的枪管膛线有八英寸缠距
That means there's enough spin
to stabilize even the heavier 70-grain bullets.
这意味着产生的旋转能使70格令的子弹稳定飞行
It's accurate.
这很准确
If you hear this thing going off,
you get out of the line of fire.
如果你听到这个家伙的声音，你要马上从它的弹道上闪开
Remember, in our exercises,
记住，在训练中
you'll be using blanks and laser-activated
MILES vests to score hits.
你们使用空包弹和激光感应背心来记录命中
But when you get into a fire fight,
the idea is not to get hit.
但是一旦你进入战场，记住不要被击中
My men are good soldiers.
They know how to fight.
我的人都是好士兵，他们知道怎样战斗
They just don't know how to duck.
可惜不知道怎样闪避
Look, Captain Ngoba, I know some of this
is straight out of the book.
看，Ngoba上尉，我知道这比书本直白
Your soldiers are courageous and brave,
你的士兵都很勇敢
but they have to fight the natural tendency
to start firing back from unsecured positions.
但是他们要反抗自然趋势，从险境中反击
Yes, we know.
You gotta aim if you want to maim.
是的，我们知道
如果你想伤害别人，你必须先瞄准
Ngoba, get your men in formation
and let's go again.
Ngoba，让你的人列队，我们再来一遍
Captain Nelson, Colonel Jäger would like
to see you in his office.
Nelson上尉，Jager上校在他的办公室等你
Brown, take over. Beckett with me.
Brown，你来替我。Beckett跟我走
- What did we do wrong?
- Maybe my transfer came through.
- 我们做错了什么？
- 也许是我的调令来了
- You leaving the Marines?
- Anything to get away from you.
- 你要离开海军陆战队？
- 没有什么会永远陪着你
- You wanted to see us, sir?
- Yes.
- 你要见我们，长官？
- 是的
New orders for tomorrow.
明天的新命令
New orders?
新命令？
Training operations
will be temporarily suspended.
训练要暂时中止
You will be taking men into the DRC.
你要带人进入刚果民主共和国
Sir, I thought it was off limits
to outside military forces.
长官，我记得那里外国军队禁止进入
The Congolese government
has cleared us for this one mission.
刚果政府已经允许我们去执行这次任务
The rebels are threatening
all Europeans in the DRC.
叛军对所有在刚果的欧洲人造成威胁
Most have moved out long ago after
the country ceased being a Belgian colony.
当这个国家不再是比利时殖民地之后，大部分人早已搬走了
But one last Belgian plantation owner,
但是最后一个比利时种植园的拥有者
a Jean Van Brunt, has refused
to respond to our communications,
Jean Van Brunt，拒绝回应我们的联络
and his property is here.
他的财产在这里
Come on.
过来
Here in Mukana, just over the border.
在Mukana，刚刚越过边境
An old-style plantation that, like its owner,
has outstayed its welcome.
一个古老的种植园，就像它的拥有者一样，老得令人生厌
Take 10 men.
带10个人
You have to go in there and extract him
and any persons still working for him.
你要去那里，救出他和他的工人
I'll take five of my Marines and Ngoba's men.
我带五个我的人，五个Ngoba的人
Good.
很好
- Yes, sir.
- Dismissed.
- 收到，长官
- 解散
Sir?
长官？
Yes, Sergeant?
怎么了，中士？
Why not airlift him out?
为什么不把他空运出来？
It's too dangerous to fly in the area,
在这个区域飞行非常危险
since the rebels have gotten their hands
on Strela missiles.
叛军装备了Strela(箭)防空导弹
If they have Strelas,
what else do they have in store for us?
如果他们连Strela都有，他们还藏着别的什么用来对付我们？
Hopefully, you don't find out.
希望你们不会找到
So we're on babysitting duty tomorrow?
所以明天我们就变成保姆了？
This is not a walk in the park.
这可不是逛公园
There's rebel activity all over that area.
那个区域里到处都是叛军
Great.
好极了
Don't worry, Paddy. We'll be in and out
before they know what hit them.
别担心，伙计。在他们发现是谁揍了他们之前我们就会出来了
- Bing-bang, like a Chinese prom date.
- Man, you're a pig, you know that?
- 就像中国的舞会？
- 伙计，你就是头猪，知道吗？
You love it.
Whoa. Check out the new chick.
哇。看这个新来的妞
Who is she?
她是谁？
She's from England.
她从英国来
That's military intel, bro.
Don't even think about it.
她是军事智囊，兄弟。
别瞎想了
What's that supposed to mean?
那是什么意思？
It means she'll want a man with brains,
and you ain't smart, even for a Marine.
她喜欢长脑子的男人
可惜你一点都不聪明，就算你是海军陆战队
Well, she's looking over here.
哦，她在往这边看
It doesn't make any sense,
but she's looking at you, dude.
那不代表什么
她在看你，伙计
Go for it, Sergeant.
She wants you all up in there.
去吧，中士
她想要你过去
Not interested.
没兴趣
Ten bucks says
you don't have the nerve to talk to her.
十块钱赌你不敢过去和她聊聊
- I'll second that.
- Yeah.
- 我同意
- 没错
You're on.
说定了
- Oh, yes.
- Oh, yeah!
- Here we go.
- Go get it, B.
See you in five minutes.
5分钟后见
Hey. I'm Sergeant Beckett.
You're new here, right?
嘿，我是Beckett中士
你是新来的，是吗？
That's it?
没了？
What?
什么？
That's your come-on line, Sergeant?
"Hey, you're new?"
这就是你的搭讪，中士？
“嘿，你是新来的？”
Yeah, I guess it's...
恩，我想是的……
It's Abramowitz.
Lieutenant Ellen Abramowitz.
我是Abramowitz
中尉Ellen Abramowitz
Work on the line, Marine.
Then get back to me.
再去多学点，大兵
然后再回来
I will.
好的
- How'd that work out?
- Fail, Sergeant.
- 结果怎样？
- 败了吧，中士
Walk of shame.
耻辱之行啊
Fraternizing with a superior officer.
和高级官员打交道
- Shot down.
- Way to go, B.
- 被击坠了
- 加油，B
You knew she was a Lieutenant.
你们知道她是中尉
You owe me 10 bucks.
你欠我10块钱
You struck out.
你失败了
The bet was to talk to her.
赌的是我和她说话
Shit.
操
What did she say?
她说什么了？
- What did you say? What did you say to her?
- Come on.
- 你怎么说的？你怎么和他说的？
- 得了
A gentleman never tells.
绅士绝不会告诉你们
Shutting him off like a light switch.
把他当作电灯开关关掉
That was pathetic.
这可真悲哀
I didn't see you talking to any women
last night.
昨天晚上我没看见你和任何女人说过话
Brown's queer for Capobianco.
Brown和Capobianco搞基
- Fuck you.
- 日你
- See?
- Busting my balls.
- 看见没？
- 滚球
Border coming up.
到边境了
There's some fly women around here.
周围有几个女人很迷人
You're gonna take them back home with you?
你想把她们带回家？
I ain't saying I'm gonna take them home.
I'm just saying...
我没说我要带她们回家
我只是说……
Yeah, yeah, yeah,
是，是，是
"I'll give you a new life."
“我会给你新的生活。”
Yeah. "Move to Utah."
是啊，“搬到犹他州。”
Guys, guys, settle down. We're almost there.
伙计们，伙计们，安静。我们就要到了
Mukana's 10 klicks north of here,
just past Uhuru.
再往北10公里就是Mukana，刚好经过Uhuru
What, they've got a town
named after the chick from Star Trek?
什么？他们把镇子取名星际迷航里那个女人？
That's Uhura, dick.
Uhuru is "freedom" in Swahili.
那是Uhura，笨蛋
Uhuru是斯瓦西里语，意思是“自由”
Check out the big brain on the...
检查下大脑子……
Bad joke,
不好笑
since the rebels have driven everyone
out of that part of the country.
叛军把所有人从这个国家的那部分赶出去
- Right. I heard they walked.
- Settle down, Vincent.
- 没错，我听说他们走了
- 安静，Vincent
Yes, this may not be Afghanistan or Fallujah,
是的，这可不是阿富汗或费卢杰
but be careful. It's the jungle of the Congo.
要小心。那里是刚果丛林
Okay, jungle faces on.
好的，丛林我们来了
Sounds like a holiday.
听起来像是度假
Hunters?
猎人？
Chandler and his rich European friends
come to get trophies.
Chandler和他的欧洲有钱朋友们来这抢战利品
I thought it was too dangerous
for Europeans in this area.
我认为欧洲人呆在这个区域里真是太危险了
Down here,
hunters are a big part of the economy.
猎人是这里主要的经济来源
They pay good money to the government
and they feed the local villagers.
他们给政府一大笔钱，还养活了当地村民
Keep your eyes open.
注意观察
And Marines, behave.
大兵们，注意礼貌
Beautiful.
真漂亮
You're Jean Van Brunt?
你是Jean Van Brunt
Who's asking?
你是谁？
Can we speak to you please, sir?
我们能和你谈谈吗，先生？
Come inside.
进来吧
- I don't understand these orders.
- It's simple. We have to take you out of here.
- 我不明白这个命令
- 很简单。我们要把你从这带走
I have no problem here.
我在这很好
- Where are your workers?
- They ran off.
- 你的工人们在哪？
- 他们早跑了
They are afraid.
他们害怕了
I'm not.
我可不怕
It's for your own protection, sir.
这是为了你的安全，先生
Leave this place? I can't.
离开这里？我不能这么干
I'm afraid we're under orders.
我们得执行任务
Screw your orders.
让你的任务见鬼去吧
This plantation was built by my father.
这个种植园是我父亲建的
It survived the Congo wars
and several small uprisings since.
它经历了刚果战争和几次起义
I'm not going to abandon
everything he lived and died for.
我不会放弃任何他为之生和为之死的东西
No. No, everything that means
anything to me is in the house
不。不，那些东西就在这所房子里
and on that land.
和外面的土地上
My wife is buried out there, for God's sake.
我的妻子就葬在外面，看在上帝的份上
You want me to walk out that door?
你们想让我走出那扇门？
I'm sorry, but you have no choice.
很抱歉，但是你别无选择
All right. I will come with you. For now.
好吧，我会跟你走，暂时
Take me to your commander. I'll talk to him.
带我去见你的指挥官。我要和他谈谈
Ngoba, get the vehicle. Let's go!
Ngoba，上车。我们走了！
- Everybody, move out!
- Okay.
- 大伙，出发了！
- 好的
Got to bring her around.
Sir, I don't know what to say,
先生，我不知道该怎么说
but when the fighting is over,
you could come back.
不过一旦战争结束，你就可以回来
To what?
An empty field where this house once stood?
为了什么？
一块这座房子曾经待过的空地？
No. If you take me out of here,
this place dies, and so do I.
不。一旦你把我从这里带走，这块地就死了，还有我
Get down!
趴下！
- Fall back!
- Run for cover!
- 退后！
- 找掩护！
Find cover!
找掩护！
He's fucking hit!
他中弹了！
Hoag, get down!
Hoag，趴下！
Get down!
趴下！
- Get fucking down!
- Hoag, get down!
- 快他妈的趴下！
- Hoag，趴下！
Get the fuck down!
他妈的趴下！
Fucking rebels.
狗日的叛军
I don't think it's a squad out there.
我觉得外面不会有很多人
Why do you say that?
为什么这么说？
His rate of fire, the radius of attack.
I think there's one guy out there.
他的开火频率，攻击范围。
我想外面只有一个人
- One guy. A sniper.
- Sniper?
- 一个人。狙击手
- 狙击手？
Fuck! Fuck!
操！操！
Where is he?
Where are those shots coming from?
他在哪？
那些子弹从哪射过来的？
- I can't tell.
- I think he stopped shooting.
- 我不知道
- 我想他停止射击了
He's playing with us.
他在耍我们
He can't see around the door.
他看不到门周围
He's moving around to a better location
to get shots.
他在寻找更好的射击地点
Maybe he's gone.
I gotta get back into my house.
也许他已经走了
我要回我的房子里
- Fuck your house!
- You don't understand...
- 去你妈的房子！
- 你不明白……
There's 50 yards of clear kill zone
between here and that tree line.
从这到那片树林有50码的空地
He can pick us off one by one.
他可以一个一个把我们干掉
But in my house, my...
但是在我的房子里，我的……
Fuck!
操！
Objective is fucked!
任务目标中弹了！
- Oh, my God.
- Damn it! Shit!
- 哦，我的上帝
- 可恶！操！
Come on, stop it!
快点止血！
It won't stop.
血止不住
Look at me!
看着我！
- Breathe, breathe, breathe.
- I messed up.
- 呼吸，呼吸，呼吸
- 我搞砸了
Breathe.
呼吸
- I can't breathe.
- You stupid fuck.
- 我没法呼吸
- 你这蠢货
Fuck it!
我操！
- Why isn't he shooting?
- He must be moving positions.
- 他为什么不开火了？
- 他肯定又在移动
- Fuck!
- Fuck what?
- 操
- 怎么了？
This is a U.S. Army shipping container.
这是美军海运集装箱
You see this case?
看这个箱子
I've packed cases like this back at Pendleton.
我在Pendleton曾经装过这个箱子
Pelican model 1780 cases.
Cases that hold 12 full-size M-16s each.
Pelican型1780弹药箱
每个箱子可以容纳12支全尺寸M16
Shit. What the hell are they doing here?
操。它们在这里干什么？
I don't know.
我不知道
Well, Captain, you got a plan, man?
呃，上尉，你有什么计划？
Against the sniper?
对付狙击手？
Well?
怎么？
Why are you looking at me? You're in charge.
你看我干什么？你是头
Aren't you the sniper expert here?
这里你是狙击专家
Well, you know more
about this shit than me, man.
你比我更了解这堆狗屎
That's beautiful.
How do we fight this motherfucker?
太好了
我们该怎么对付这个混帐？
We wait until darkness falls.
我们要等待天暗下来
Well, what if he has NODs?
如果他有夜视仪怎么办？
Night vision only works in darkness.
夜视仪只在黑夜中起作用
We'll make our move right at dusk.
我们在黄昏行动
He won't be able to use his NOD.
His day vision will be compromised.
他没法用夜视仪
而肉眼观察又受到很大影响
That's our best chance.
那是我们最好的机会
And if we can't get out of here?
如果我们没法离开这呢？
Then what? Walk back to Zimbala?
成功之后呢？我们走回Zimbala？
Those motherfuckers
walked us into an ambush.
那些混帐把我们带进了陷阱
We're on our own here, man!
You led us into a fucking ambush!
我们只能自力更生，伙计！
你把我们带进了一个陷阱！
I am going home. I am going home.
我要回家，我要回家
Two tours in fucking Iraq, one in Afghanistan
and to die in Africa like this?
去过两次伊拉克，一次阿富汗，然后像这样死在非洲？
Fuck that, man. Fuck them!
去他妈的，伙计。去他妈的！
Cease fire!
别开枪！
Fuck! Fuck!
操！操！
We're dead, man. We're fucking dead.
我们要死了，伙计。我们要死了
Not yet. Not yet.
还没有，还没有
Sun's going down. We gotta move together.
太阳要落山了。我们要一起行动
Okay. Which way?
好的，走哪边？
The trees by the road are closest.
We kick the door, but we run for it.
最近的是路边的树林。
踹开门，然后赶快跑
He'll have trouble with us moving fast.
他会跟不上我们的速度
You sound like you believe that shit.
听起来你很信任那个混蛋
I have to.
我只能这样
Ten bucks says
you don't make it to that tree line.
十块钱赌你到不了树林边
You're on.
说定了
Now.
现在
You're hit. You're gonna get yourself...
你中弹了。你一个人待着吧……
Relax.
放松
Where am I?
我在哪？
You're in my camp.
这是我的营地
- You're the hunter.
- Yeah. Martin Chandler.
- 你是个猎人
- 是的。Martin Chandler
You got a name, kid?
你有名字吧，小伙子？
Beckett. Sergeant Brandon Beckett.
Beckett。Brandon Beckett中士
Okay, Brandon,
you want to let go of my arm?
好的，Brandon
可以松开我的胳膊吗？
Sorry.
抱歉
What were you gonna do with that knife?
你要用那把刀做什么？
I was gonna try and get
the bullet out of your shoulder.
我正要尝试从你的肩膀里取出子弹
It's a clean entry, but it's gone in too deep.
创口很干净，但是子弹很深
Where are you going?
You've got to get to a real hospital.
你要去哪？
你得找个正规医院
That wound's gonna get infected.
You're lucky to be alive.
伤口会感染的
你还活着真幸运
How did I get here?
我怎么会在这里？
I was scouting for kudu
when I heard the shots.
我在搜寻羚羊的时候听到了枪声
By the time I got there, it was all over.
等我赶到的时候，一切都结束了
The plantation. I gotta get back there.
种植园。我要回那里去
No, it's too dangerous.
不行，太危险了
Try and stop me.
试试看阻止我
Who are these kids?
这些孩子是什么人？
They're orphans.
Their parents were killed in the war.
他们是孤儿
他们的父母都在战争中死了
- I'm helping Duku protect them.
- They live here?
- 我帮Duku保护他们
- 他们住在这里？
The rebels are always looking
for new soldiers.
叛军一直在寻找新战士
They force the young boys to join them
and threaten to kill their families.
他们威胁要杀掉男孩子的家人们，强迫他们加入
Sometimes just kill their families.
有时候就直接杀掉他们的家人
These are the sort of people
you're up against, huh?
这就是你正在对付的人，恩？
Can you give me directions
back to the plantation?
你能告诉我回种植园的方向吗？
A map of some type?
I can't leave my friends out there.
一张地图？
我不能把朋友们丢在外面
Look, I knew Van Brunt. He was my friend.
我认识Van Brunt。他是我的朋友
He helped me set this place up
in the early stages.
他帮助我建立了这个地方的雏形
And he helped me with supplies
when rebels cut off the shipments.
当叛军切断物资时，也是他给我们补给
I also want to see his memory served.
我也想看到他的努力起作用
By letting the people who killed him
get away?
那就让杀掉他的人逍遥法外？
Okay.
好吧
So you'll take me?
你会带我回去？
Yeah. I'm also crazy.
是啊，我也是个疯子
These hunters are going out
early in the morning to shoot buffalo.
这些猎人们早上要去捕猎野牛
I'll take you to the plantation,
but I gotta get back before they leave.
我会带你去种植园，但是我必须在他们离开前回来
How do I thank you?
我该怎么感谢你
Just don't get me killed.
别让我被杀掉
This is where I found the bodies.
这是我发现尸体的地方
- Where are they?
- They were here.
- 尸体在哪？
- 他们曾经在这
You were the only one alive.
你是唯一的幸存者
So someone took them?
有人带走了他们？
Yeah.
是的
Let's check the house.
我们检查下房子
They don't leave much unturned.
他们几乎翻遍了这里
Fucking rebels.
混帐叛军
You do business with them?
你和他们做生意？
I trade them game meat
so they don't kill my clients.
我给他们野味，而他们就不会杀我的客户
The same thing.
一个德行
Yeah, yeah. I'll go upstairs.
是啊是啊。我去楼上看看
Put that down.
把那个放下
Give that to me.
把那个给我
Just hold on. We're not gonna hurt you.
请等一下，我们不会伤害你
You killed my father.
你杀了我父亲
I should kill you right now.
我现在就该杀了你
No, I didn't. I was here to help him.
不，不是我。我来这是要帮助他
I don't believe you.
我不相信你
Kelli?
Okay. Okay. Putting my gun down.
好的好的。我把枪放下
- I'm a friend of your father's.
- My father had a lot of friends.
- 我是你父亲的朋友
- 我父亲有很多朋友
He would have spoken about me.
I'm Chandler.
他一定提起过我
我是Chandler
- The hunter?
- Yeah.
- 那个猎人？
- 没错
I didn't know you'd be here.
我不知道你会在这里
Okay, you say you knew my father. Prove it.
好吧，你说你认识我父亲。拿出证据
Okay. He said you were away at school.
好的。他说过你在外面上学
Where?
在哪里？
In Brugge. You're staying with your aunt.
Is that correct?
Brugge。你和你姑妈住在一起，对吗？
- Yes.
- Thank God you're okay.
- 是的
- 谢天谢地你没事
You should come with us.
We can get you out of...
你可以和我们走，我们会带你离开……
And who are you?
你又是谁？
My name is Brandon Beckett,
with the United States Marine Corps.
我是Brandon Beckett，在美国海军陆战队服役
In the Congo?
在刚果？
Working for the UN.
为联合国工作
They sent us here
to take your father back to our base.
他们派我们来带你父亲回我们的基地
They knew there was trouble with the rebels.
他们知道这里的叛军很麻烦
Rebels didn't kill my father.
叛军没杀我的父亲
Her father had hidden her in the safe room.
她的父亲把她藏在安全的房间
I was pretty sure we'd been cut down
by a single shooter.
我确信我们被一个射手杀掉
But Kelli said she'd heard looters
in the house who spoke English.
但是Kelli说她听到在房子里抢劫的人说英语
Maybe it was the same pack
who attacked Chandler's camp.
也许和袭击Chandler营地的是同一伙人
They're taking the children.
他们要带走孩子们
Kelli, get down!
Kelli，趴下！
Get down!
趴下！
Where the hell is Chandler?
Chandler去哪了？
Clear.
安全
Chandler!
- Were they looking for me?
- No, supplies and children.
- 他们在找我吗？
- 不，找补给和孩子们
Why did they take them?
他们为什么要带走孩子们？
They'll force them to fight for them.
他们要强迫孩子们为他们打仗
Give a 12-year-old boy a rifle,
and they call him a soldier.
发给12岁男孩一支步枪，然后他们就叫他战士
We have to get back to the base.
Can I borrow one of your vehicles?
我得回基地。我可以借一辆车吗？
Duku.
They've stolen everything
but the Land Rover we had.
他们偷走了所有东西，但我们还有路虎
I've got to use it to track down the rebels
and find the children.
我要开着它追叛军，找到孩子们
- Are you coming?
- I can't.
- 你来吗？
- 我不能去
I've got to turn Kelli over to base authorities.
我得把Kelli带回基地
How will we get back?
我们怎么回去？
We'll walk.
走回去
We can't be more than
four klicks to the border.
我们离边境最多四公里
- You don't know the bush well enough.
- I know how to use a compass.
- 你还不了解丛林
- 我知道怎么用指南针
Do you have a compass?
你有指南针？
East, west.
这是东，这是西
The border is straight east from here.
从这往东直走就是边境
It's too risky.
这太冒险了
We'll be okay.
我们会没事的
Not with that you won't.
你们没戏
Take this.
带上这个
It's fine for rebels, but if you run into
big game, that'll just piss them off.
应付叛军很管用，但是如果你陷入大混乱，这只会使他们生气
Take this.
再带上这个
It's not loaded
and the shells are in the side pocket.
没装弹，弹药在侧袋里
Thanks. I'll bring it back.
谢谢。我会把它带回来的
That's if you live. Keep off the roads.
Good luck.
你得先活着。远离大路
祝你好运
Why didn't your father tell us
you were in the house?
为什么你的父亲没告诉我们你在房子里
He didn't know you. He was scared, I guess.
他不认识你们。他吓坏了，我想
But I thought he didn't have any enemies.
What would he have been scared of?
可是我以为他没有敌人
是什么吓到他了？
I don't know, but he was worried.
不知道，但是他很烦恼
I could tell.
告诉我
Why would this have happened?
为什么会发生这种事？
Can you tell me that?
My father was everyone's friend.
告诉我为什么
我父亲是所有人的朋友
I guess anything I say right now
isn't going to help.
我想我现在说什么都没用
That's right.
是的
Your mother?
你母亲？
She died when I was 10.
我十岁时她死了
My father knew I needed a family,
so he sent me to live with my aunt.
我父亲知道我需要一个家
所以他把我送到了姑妈家
Finally, when I'm old enough,
最后，当我长大
I came 6,000 kilometers to see my father,
only to lose him.
我跨过6000公里来看我父亲
却失去了他
Now I have no one.
现在我没有亲人了
Kelli, you don't know me,
but you have to trust me.
Kelli，你不了解我，不过你得相信我
The men who did this to your father,
I'm going to find them.
杀掉你父亲的人，我会找到的
I swear.
我发誓
Let's go.
我们走吧
Your wound is bleeding. Are you all right?
你的伤口在流血。你还好吗？
Yeah, great. Never better.
是的，很好。再好不过了
- You're lying.
- Was it at all convincing?
- 你撒谎
- 不相信？
No.
不
It's not much further. We'll make it.
没多远了。我们就快到了
Is that more lying?
又在撒谎？
If it is, then I'm lying to myself, too.
如果是，那我也在欺骗我自己
United Nations!
联合国！
I have to get back. I have to get back.
我得回去。我得回去
Medic! Radio the UN base!
医生！联系联合国基地！
His wound has gone septic.
We need to get him to the hospital now!
他的伤口腐烂了
我们得马上把他送到医院！
What will happen to him?
他会怎么样？
You do not want to feel any strain
on your muscles.
不要让你的肌肉绷紧
If you feel stressed, you will not be able
to hold that position without moving.
如果你感觉紧张，你就没法保持稳定
You move, you give away your position.
你动了，你就离开了你的位置
You move, you die.
你动了，你就死了
Now breathe and fire at will.
现在呼吸，自由射击
Once you have your mission,
当你执行任务时
the most important thing for you to do
is identify the location of your hide.
最重要的就是确定你的藏身之地
Now for this, you will use intel.
You will use satellite maps.
为了达到这个目的，你要运用智慧
要用到卫星地图
You will use good
old-fashioned reconnaissance.
也会用到过时但好用的勘测技术
Nakelski, what are we looking for
in the final firing position?
Nakelski，最佳射击位置有什么要求？
Maximum field of fire
and observation of target area,
最大观察和射击范围
concealment from enemy
and clear evac route.
高度隐蔽和安全撤退路线
God damn it, son. You are absolutely right.
小子。完全正确
A hide that seems good to you
will also seem good to the enemy.
在你看来不错的隐藏点，敌人一样会想到
So you want to avoid high spots like towers,
随意最好避开高处，比如塔
like crests of hills
that will get you silhouetted.
比如山顶会暴露你的身影
- Sir.
- Don't salute me, son. I have no rank.
- 长官
- 别向我敬礼，小子。我没有军阶
Thank you, all the same.
谢谢
Once you establish your FFP,
一旦你建立最终射击位置
you may have to hold this position
for several days.
你可能要在那里待上好几天
- Days, sir? How do you...
- You don't.
- 好几天，长官？要怎样……
- 不怎样
You piss your pants and learn to love it.
I love it so much I'm doing it right now.
你要习惯尿在内裤上
我喜欢这样而且现在我正这么做
You do not get to use the can
till your mission is completed. Savvy?
直到任务结束你才能去厕所。Savvy？
- Sir.
- Now breathe, fire at will.
- 长官
- 呼吸，自由射击
That must have been a bad one.
那一定是个噩梦
Yeah. I'm burning up.
是啊。我很热
Drink up.
喝掉
Slow down. You'll drown, Sergeant.
慢点。你会淹死的，中士
Where am I?
我在哪
Zimbala, the UN base.
Zimbala，联合国基地
It was touch and go for a while,
but your fever broke today.
有一段时间你很糟糕，不过今天你退烧了
You're really lucky you got here in time.
很幸运你能及时到这里
- The girl?
- She's safe. Safe and sound.
- 那个女孩呢？
- 她很安全。安然无恙
I count the holes.
我数过小洞
What?
什么？
Little holes there in the acoustic ceiling.
I count them.
在天花板上的小洞，我数过它们
It helps.
很有用
That helps you sleep?
帮助你入睡？
No.
不是
It helps me stop thinking
about the friends I lost, men I killed.
它让我不再想我死去的兄弟，我杀掉的人
You've killed a lot of men?
你杀过很多人？
Enough.
足够多
Killing ain't hard, kid.
It's just pulling the trigger.
杀人不难，孩子。扣下扳机就行
It's living with it after. That's hard.
难的是杀人之后活下去
Who are you, sir?
你是谁，先生？
My name is Miller.
我叫Miller
I'm a friend of your father's,
here to take you home.
我是你父亲的朋友，来带你回家
Excuse me.
抱歉
He cut us down like wheat.
他像割麦子一样杀掉我们
My men died. I should have died with them.
我的人都死了。我本该和他们一起死的
I fell down and I lived. They were killed.
我倒下了却活着。他们都死了
What you're feeling, kid,
it's called survivor guilt.
你现在的感觉，孩子，
通常被称为幸存者的内疚
It's irrational, but it's normal.
这很荒谬，但是也很正常
Someplace inside,
you know it's not your fault.
在内心某处，你知道这不是你的错
You just gotta find that place.
你只要找到那个地方
I know what I need to find.
我知道我要找到什么
What? The sniper? And then what?
什么？那个狙击手？还是别的？
Kill him.
杀掉他
You can't fight something
you don't understand.
你没法和未知作战
Hey.
嘿
Being a sniper is something completely
different than being a field trooper.
成为游骑兵和成为狙击手是完全不同的方法
So I should what? Become a sniper?
所以我该怎样？变成狙击手？
No way.
没门
All that sneaky shit?
那些鬼鬼祟祟的垃圾？
That's not fighting, sir.
那不是战斗，先生
Brandon, I know who your father is.
Brandon，我知道你的父亲是怎样的人
So do I.
我也是
Warfare is fighting face to face
in the battlefield.
战争是在战场上面对面的打仗
Sniping the enemy from a hiding place?
That's pure chicken shit.
躲在一个隐蔽的地方狙击敌人？
那完全是胆小鬼的玩意
You gotta face your enemy.
你得面对你的敌人
Is that how you're gonna fight your sniper,
up-close and personal?
那就是你对付狙击手的办法？单枪匹马冲上去？
- I'll figure it out.
- Newsflash, kid.
- 我会解决的
- 最新消息，小子
Half the Congo is at war. It is not our war.
半个刚果都在打仗。这不是我们的战争
It's time to go home.
该回家了
You can go if you want. I'm not finished here.
你想走你走。我在这里还没完
You're weak.
你很虚弱
Your wounds are still healing.
你的伤口还未痊愈
I think I'll stick around.
我想我还得多留几天
Do whatever you want.
It doesn't matter to me.
随你想做什么。都和我无关
Good night.
晚安
On your feet.
站起来
What are we doing?
我们这是干什么？
Quiet. Take this.
安静。拿着这个
There, by the perimeter tower.
那里，边上那座塔
- You see the sentry?
- I see the back of his head.
- 看到哨兵了吗？
- 我看到他的后脑
Good. Shoot him.
很好。向他射击
- You want me to shoot him?
- He is your target. Take him out.
- 你要我向他射击？
- 他是你的目标。干掉他
Who is he?
他是谁？
He's leaking information to the rebels.
他向叛军走漏情报
Now you have your assignment.
Take him out.
现在你有任务。干掉他
- Look, I don't even know who this...
- You don't need to know.
- 嘿，我甚至还不知道他是……
- 你不需要知道
What's the distance?
距离多少？
- Two hundred yards.
- And how do you know that?
- 200码
- 你怎么知道的？
- Through the scope. He's 10 mils high.
- Good. Switch him off.
- 通过望远镜。他只有1厘米高
- 很好。干掉他
What are you waiting for, sniper?
You have your assignment. Shoot.
你在等什么，狙击手？
你有任务。射击
- No.
- No?
- 不
- 不？
- I need to know more...
- What do you need to know?
- 我需要知道……
- 你想知道什么？
That man is the fucking enemy.
You put a bullet in his head.
那个人是他妈的敌人
你要把子弹射到他的头里去
I don't kill indiscriminately.
我不会随便杀人
Correction. You don't follow orders.
订正。你不会服从命令
You're not ready to take on a sniper, kid,
你还没准备好变成狙击手，小子
because he would shoot that man
on command.
因为狙击手会按照命令射击
Empty.
空的
So, end of the lesson.
所以，课程结束
Captain Ngoba, according to your report,
Ngoba上尉，根据你的报告
your men were in a direct attack,
你的人曾遭遇一次直接攻击
and you were separated
from the rest of the unit.
而你又和剩下的人被分开
Once you determined
your men had been killed
当你得知你的人被杀
and lacking sufficient cover,
you chose to retreat to base.
而你又缺少足够的掩护，你决定撤回基地
- And leave the rest of us to die.
- Sergeant!
- 不管我们剩下的人死活
- 中士！
- Is that a correct reading of your report?
- Yes, sir.
- 对你的报告的解释没错吧？
- 是的，长官
That will be all, Captain.
就这样，上尉
Lieutenant Abramowitz,
do we know who these attackers were?
Abramowitz中尉，知道攻击者从哪里来吗？
It seems like a squad-sized force.
看起来像是一小队武装分子
However, I think it may have been
one shooter.
但是，我认为只有一个射手
That seems unlikely, no?
那不太可能，是吧？
The medics removed a Russian .30 caliber
rifle round from his shoulder.
医生从他的肩膀里取出一颗苏制.30口径步枪子弹
One hundred forty-seven grains,
one in 11.5-inch twist.
147格令，11.5英寸缠距
Are you sure about the twist?
你确定是那个缠距？
It's what it says here.
这上面是这么写的
Colonel, the rebels use Soviet weapons.
上校，叛军使用苏制武器
Their 7.62mm sniper rifle
uses a one in nine-inch twist.
他们的7.62mm狙击步枪是9英寸缠距
One in 11 .5. That's one of ours.
11.5英寸。那是我们的武器
- Ours?
- The M-24 U.S. Sniping System barrel
- 我们的？
- M-24美军狙击系统枪管
uses that twist.
使用那个缠距
Whoever it was used a U.S. sniper rifle
chambered for the Russian round.
有人曾把苏制子弹装填进美军狙击步枪
There are millions of weapons
of every caliber in this country.
在这个国家有几百万种武器，所有口径都有
Sir, if I may, just one more thing.
长官，还有一件事情
Ballistic suggests it was a sniper,
弹道分析结果认为那是一个狙击手
but it must have been a squad
that returned and sanitized the scene.
不过一定有一个小队回来过打扫战场
They removed the bodies,
cleared Van Brunt's house
他们搬走了尸体，清理了Van Brunt的房子
and made it look like looting.
还把那里布置成被洗劫的样子
So? We'll never know.
所以？我们什么都不会知道
Thank you for your report.
谢谢你的报告
That's it?
就完了？
My men were shot
by what may have been U.S. weapons,
我的人被美军的武器打中
and you say, "Thanks for the report"?
而你就说，“谢谢你的报告”？
Sergeant, we've done all we can do.
中士，我们已经做了所有能做的
Doesn't look like you've done anything.
看起来你什么都没做
The Colonel means the UN doesn't have
the time or manpower to investigate.
上校的意思是联合国没有时间或人力去调查
Don't you care about what happened?
你们不关心发生了什么吗？
That's beside the point.
那不重要
The conflict in the DRC is a flashpoint.
发生在刚果的冲突是一个导火索
The government can topple any day.
政府随时可能被推翻
We have no idea
how this will affect diplomatic relations.
我们不知道这会对外交关系有什么影响
I can look into it on my own.
我可以自己去调查
Oh, no. That's the last thing we need.
哦，算了。那是我们最不需要的
We cannot afford you
running into the middle
我们不会支持你
of an international incident
like a cowboy, Sergeant.
像个牛仔一样跑到一场国际事件中间去，中士
Until further notice,
you are confined to base.
在收到通知之前，你被限制在基地内
Yeah, Captain? What do you want?
I heard your story back there.
怎么，上尉？你想怎样？
我在后面听到了你的故事
No, you did not, Sergeant.
不，你没有，中士
Your men do not respect my men.
We both know this.
你的人不尊重我的人，我们都清楚这点
But we are African soldiers
and you are Marines.
但是我们是非洲战士，而你们是海军陆战队
That does not mean you can judge me.
那不意味着你们可以审判我
This is my country.
这是我的国家
We did not ask for you and people like you
to come here.
我们没请求你和你这样的人跑到这来
It is unfortunate about your men,
but I did what I thought was best at the time.
你的人很不幸
可是我在那时做了我认为最好的行动
Brandon?
They told me you were still here.
I was surprised.
他们告诉我你还在这里。我很惊讶
They're still trying to contact my aunt.
They told me you might die.
他们还在尝试联系我的姑妈
他们告诉我你可能死了
The medics always make it sound
worse than it is
医生总是危言耸听
so they can look like miracle workers
when you pull through.
所以当你恢复健康的时候，他们就像是奇迹制造者
I brought you some DVDs.
The Michael Jackson movie, Jonas Brothers.
我给你带了一些DVD
Michael Jackson的电影，Jonas兄弟乐队
You know, some of my favorites.
你看，是一些我喜欢的
These are code five. Won't work in Belgium.
这些是五区的。比利时看不了
Maybe you can trade them.
你可以卖掉它们
Kelli, have you had any more thoughts about
who may have wanted to kill your father?
Kelli，关于谁想杀掉你父亲，你有没有别的想法？
I already told that woman.
我已经告诉了那个女人
- Abramowitz?
- Same as I told you.
- Abramowitz？
- 和跟你说的一样
I don't know anyone who would.
我不知道还有谁
In the house, there was a picture
of your father with some soldiers.
在房子里，有一张你父亲和一些士兵的合影
It wasn't there when we went back.
You know the one?
当我们回去的时候它没了。你知道吗？
Yes.
是的
Was your father in the army?
你的父亲在军队里？
No. But he would let the soldiers
come to our plantation. He traded with them.
没有。不过他会让士兵们来我们的种植园
他和他们做生意
Did he trade with the rebels?
他和叛军有生意来往么？
He traded with the rebels, tribes
and the Congolese army.
他和叛军、当地部落以及刚果军队都有生意
He had to, to keep our home safe.
为了我们家的安全，他只能这么做
Sorry. I'm not used to the Officers' Mess.
抱歉。我不习惯军官餐厅
It's been a long time
since I've seen a tablecloth.
我上次看见桌布是很久以前了
Ma'am.
女士
Here you go, sir.
这是你的，先生
The Dover sole is amazing.
多佛鲽鱼很不错
You rather have an MRE?
还是你更喜欢军用干粮？
No, no. This is great.
不，不。这个太棒了
So, what do you want from me?
那么，你想要我做什么？
Well, you've asked me to dinner.
Can't just be because you find me attractive.
你邀请我共进晚餐
不会只是因为你发现我很有吸引力吧
I think you know more than you're letting on.
我觉得你在装糊涂
You spoke to Kelli.
You know her father traded with the rebels.
你和Kelli谈过
你知道她的父亲和叛军有生易
Why did they kill him?
他们为什么要杀了他
Between you and I,
the UN may be moving out of here soon.
这事只在这说说
联合国不久以后就要从这里撤离了
Chances are it was more than a rebel attack.
可能遭遇叛军的攻击
Even if I did have the authority to help,
it's just me and four computer operators.
即使我有权利帮助你
也只有我和四名计算机操作员
We just don't have the resources.
我们没有资源
I know I can track him down.
我可以找到他
It would be a suicide mission.
那就是个自杀任务
Mukana was a known hotspot,
even before you got ambushed.
在你们遭遇伏击之前
Mukana就是个很出名的热点地区
Let it go.
算了吧
If it was your men, would you let it go?
如果那是你的人，你会就这么算了？
I've seen your records.
我看过你的记录
Three suspensions during high school,
高中有三次被停学
disciplinary action in each of your two years
of junior college.
初中的两年各有一次纪律处分
I had a problem being told what to do.
我不喜欢被人约束
So you joined the Marines?
所以你进了海军陆战队？
I thought it would help me get over that.
我觉得这会帮助我克服这些
- Did it?
- I guess not.
- 成功了吗？
- 我想没有
Here I am in the principal's office again.
现在我又在主管的办公室里了
So tell me, how did you get here?
告诉我，你怎么做到这步的？
Why would you want to know about me?
为什么你想要了解我？
Clearly, you've done your research on me.
显然，你已经研究过我了
Am I not allowed
to know something about you?
而不允许我稍微了解下你？
Look, I mean, if it's too embarrassing...
那个，我说，如果这很为难……
My father was a sergeant major
in the SAS at Hereford.
我父亲是Hereford的SAS军士长
I grew up on the base.
我在基地里长大
That must have been fun.
那一定很有趣
Fun? Who know.
有趣？谁知道
But it was interesting
to grow up surrounded by people
不过周围都是致力于将生命贡献给更崇高的事业的人，他们的国家
that had dedicated their lives to something
grander than themselves. Their country.
在这些人中间长大确实很有意思
So, I followed in his footsteps.
所以我就跟在父亲的足迹后面
Is that what you wanted to hear?
这是你想听的吗？
Rule number one. Know your enemy.
规则一，了解你的敌人
I'm not your enemy, Brandon.
我不是你的敌人，Brandon
It feels that way.
感觉像是
- Did I hurt it?
- No.
- 我弄疼你了吗？
- 没有
You didn't do anything.
你没做什么
It wasn't your fault that you survived.
你活着不是你的错
What's important is that you did.
重要的是你做了什么
It doesn't feel that way.
我不会这么想
Howdy.
你好
Where are you going?
你要去哪？
For a walk.
散步
Into the Congo?
去刚果？
If you go up against a sniper
in your condition,
如果你想以现在这样子去对付狙击手
you're going to get yourself killed.
你就是去找死
I'm a Marine.
我是海军陆战队
I came into this world kicking
and screaming,
我降生时又踢又叫
covered in someone else's blood.
身上覆盖着别人的血
I have no problem going out the same way.
我以同样的方式走出去不会有任何问题
Look, kid, last night was what we called
a "stress fire" exercise.
嘿，小子，昨晚我们进行的是“强迫开火”练习
Every sniper goes through it.
Hell, I went through it. It's just a test.
每一个狙击手都要通过它
我也通过了。那只是个测试
And I failed, right? But you, you can save me.
我失败了，对吧？但是你，你会救我的
Not until you get yourself into trouble.
除非你有麻烦
Sergeant Beckett, do you mean
that this office is expected to believe
Beckett中士，你想让本办事处相信
that you went AWOL
to find your squad's assailants?
你擅离职守是为了找到攻击你们小队的人？
Yes, sir.
是的，先生
What did you think you were gonna do?
你当时怎么想的
I needed help.
我需要帮助
In all of Africa, I knew there was one man
who could help me get to the rebels.
在整个非洲，我知道有一个人能帮我接近叛军
I needed to track down where the rebels
were getting these weapons,
我需要找到叛军得到这些武器的地方
including the one I was shot with.
包括击中我的那支枪
I was hoping that's how I'd find the sniper.
我希望这可以帮我找到那个狙击手
Here.
拿着
You.
你
Here.
拿着
Ma'am, it's okay. It's okay.
女士，没事。没事
I just came to bring your gun back.
我把你的枪带回来了
- Why the hell did you come back here?
- I need your help.
- 你他妈的为什么回来了
- 我需要你的帮助
The sniper who shot me,
he's out there working with the rebels.
那个击中我的狙击手，在为叛军工作
- I need to find him.
- How the hell can I help you?
- 我要找到他
- 我要怎么帮你？
Listen, I'll help you get your kids back
if you take me to the rebels.
听着，如果你把我带到叛军那里，我会帮你把孩子们找回来
I know where they're getting the guns.
我知道他们从哪拿到的武器
Come on, son.
来把，孩子
Africa is a place more alive
than any you've ever been to.
非洲是你去过的地方中最有活力的
You heed her rules,
and she'll take care of you.
你遵守她的规则，她就会关心你
You stray, and your bones
will bleach in tomorrow's sun.
如果你乱跑，明天的太阳就会照在你的骨头上
Now, if you're up against an enemy
that can kill you,
现在，如果你要对抗会杀掉你的敌人
that first clean bore shot
could save your life.
先清理干净枪管可能会救你的命
Another patch.
再补充一点
There is a chance that they can kill you
before you even get close to your target.
很可能在你接近你的目标前他们就会杀了你
I'll get to my target.
我会接近我的目标
Are you sure about that?
你能保证吗？
Soldiers just bull their way into situations.
It's the way they're trained.
士兵们总会用说大话使自己进入状态
他们就是这么训练的
But a hunter's got to stalk.
猎人必须保持隐匿
When he's stalking,
he's gotta use the terrain to his advantage.
当猎人潜行时，他会利用地形制造优势
It's basic training.
这是基本训练
No. There's more to it than that.
不，这里面有很多学问
When you're stalking your prey,
you gotta become one with the land.
当你潜行靠近猎物时
你要和大地融为一体
You probably know that
from your father, huh?
也许你已经从你父亲那学过，恩？
Unfortunately, no. I never knew him that well.
很不幸，没有。我从来不知道他有那么棒
I became a grunt to spite him.
我当兵就是为了气他
And what does he think about that?
那他是怎么想的？
I don't know.
我不知道
The men who attacked my camp.
袭击我的营地的人
Criminals led by a man that claims himself
the spokesperson of God.
带领那些罪犯的人自称是神的代言人
- There will be no negotiating.
- I wasn't expecting any.
- 没法谈判
- 我也没指望过
Shit.
操
- Those are your kids.
- Yeah.
- 那是你的孩子们
- 没错
They're going to take them
to the other rebel camps.
他们要把孩子们带到别的营地
I got to get them out of there now.
我得马上把他们救出来
Okay, if you can distract them,
I'll make my way down there behind them.
好的，如果你能转移他们的注意力
我可以溜到他们后面去
Are you up for this?
你准备好了吗？
Let's do it.
干吧
Okay.
好的
Someone's helping us.
有人在帮我们
There's someone else out there.
外面还有别人
No! He's on our side.
不！他是我们这边的
Who the hell is this?
你到底是谁？
Martin Chandler, this is Richard Miller.
Martin Chandler，这位是Richard Miller
You never told me your rank.
你还没告诉过我你的军阶
Not important. How you doing?
那不重要。你怎么样？
So, you're a spook?
你是个密探？
Friendly ghost.
友好的幽灵
Okay, guys. Help each other, find everyone
and get on that truck, okay?
好了，伙计们。互相帮助
把所有人找齐然后上那辆卡车，好吗？
What are you doing here?
你在这做什么？
I'm here to save your life.
我来救你的命
Never met you before,
but you flew halfway around the world
我以前没见过你，不过你飞了半个地球过来
just to give me a ride home.
就是为了送我回家？
Right. You know something.
是的。你知道什么
I know snipers aren't sent
to kill squads of men.
我知道狙击手不会被派来杀掉一个小队
They're assigned a specific target.
他们应该被分配到特殊目标
Your men were collateral damage.
Van Brunt was the primary target.
你的人只是附带的
Van Brunt是主要目标
How do you know all of this?
你是怎么知道的？
I know who the sniper is.
我知道狙击手是谁
I trained him.
我训练的他
- What?
- They call him The Italian.
- 什么？
- 他们叫他‘意大利人’
But he's not Italian,
he's not Russian or Somalian.
不过他不是意大利人
也不是俄罗斯人或索马里人
His name is Vincent Masiello,
and he's an American. He's a Marine.
他叫Vincent Masiello
他是美国人。是海军陆战队
We were shot by one of our own. Why?
我们被一个自己人射杀？为什么？
I don't know why.
我不知道
All I know is that order had to come
from pretty high up in the chain of command.
我只知道命令是从很高级的管理层下来的
Operation like that, I have to assume
这种操作手段，我不得不推测
they wanted to keep Van Brunt
from revealing delicate information.
他们想要阻止Van Brunt泄露敏感信息
He was the one supplying U.S. weapons
to the rebels.
他是叛军的美军武器供应商
Then he must have got them
from somebody on our side.
他一定是从我们这里的某人那里拿到武器
That's the kind of something the military
would want to keep from the public.
那正是军队想对公众隐瞒的
Is that why you're here?
Are you part of this cover-up?
那就是你来这的原因？
你也是这个掩饰的一部分？
If I were, we wouldn't be talking.
You'd be dead.
如果我是，我们就不会在这谈话了
你已经死了
I'm not here on anyone's orders.
我来这不是任何人的命令
When I heard Tom Beckett's son
was ambushed in Africa,
当我听说Tom Beckett的儿子在非洲遭到伏击
I decided to get my ass down here
and bring him back before he got killed.
我就决定赶过去，在他被杀掉前带他回来
Why do you care?
为什么你这么担心？
I care because I knew your father.
我担心是因为我认识你父亲
He was my friend. He was my teacher.
He taught me how to be a sniper.
他是我的朋友。他是我的老师
他教我怎么做一个狙击手
And he saved my life.
而且他救过我的命
Look, I'm not going back until I'm done here.
恩，除非我把这事了了，不然我不会回去
Does that include your funeral?
Because you will never see Masiello coming.
要包括你的葬礼吗？
因为你永远不会看到Masiello
Then I need to make him come to me.
那么我就需要让他来找我
Hello?
喂？
- Ellen.
- Brandon?
Where the hell are you?
你到底在哪？
I know who killed our men.
我知道是谁杀了我们的人
I need protection.
You have to send a team to come pick me up.
我需要保护。你得派支队伍来接我
You know I don't have the authority
to do that.
你知道我没有权力这么做
I'll be right on the border.
我会在边境线上
An abandoned village east
of Van Brunt's plantation named Uhuru.
Van Brunt的种植园东边
一个废弃的村子，叫Uhuru
Okay. I'll see what I can do.
好吧。我看看我能做什么
Thanks.
谢谢
You can trust her?
你可以相信她？
I don't have to.
我没必要相信
If the conspiracy is coming from the base,
it won't be legit UN force that'll show up.
如果阴谋出自基地，联合国军队不会光明正大的来
It'll be Masiello, coming to kill me.
来的会是Masiello，他会来杀我
Colonel, I found him.
上校，我找到他了
Uhuru, it's a town
on the Zimbala-DRC border. 1300 today.
Uhuru，那个镇在Zimbala和刚果交界处。今天13：00
I cannot risk any more of the men
in my command.
我不能让我的人再冒任何危险
Beckett says he has evidence of the soldiers
who ambushed his men.
Beckett说他有关于伏击他们的人的证据
It takes too long to get permission
要从现在的临时政府
from whoever passes
for today's provisional government.
获得通行许可要花很长时间
We won't need a full-scale operation.
我们不需要全面行动
I could get him myself.
我可以自己去找到他
You'll need a security detail.
你需要一个护卫小队
I want four of your best men to escort her.
Get in there and get out as fast as you can.
我要你派四个你最好的手下护送她
以最快速度进去然后出来
Yes, Colonel.
是，上校
Thank you, sir.
谢谢你，长官
I'll get the kids across the border,
then I'll come back and help you.
我要把孩子们带过边境，然后我会回来帮你
Not your fight, my friend.
这不是你的战争，我的朋友
- Are you sure?
- Yeah.
- 你确定？
- 是的
Where will you go?
你们会去哪？
Out of the Congo.
离开刚果
Zambia. Maybe Namibia.
赞比亚。也许纳米比亚
It's good hunting there.
At least they'll be safe.
那很适合打猎，最起码那里很安全
Thank you.
谢谢你
This is going to get hairy.
事情开始复杂了
I'm ready.
我准备好了
Masiello.
Drive.
开车
He's not coming alone.
他不会一个人来
You're gonna have to engage the primary
attack house to house. Pick your spots.
你得挨家挨户抵抗敌人进攻
选好你的位置
Is the com working?
通讯正常吗？
- Loud and clear.
- Good.
- 很清楚
- 很好
And one more thing.
还有一件事
Here. It's an LAR Grizzly Mark I.
拿着。这是LAR Grizzly Mark I手枪
I didn't know we had an artillery piece.
我不知道我们还有一门大炮
A little souvenir your father gave me.
你父亲留给我的纪念品
In case he gets up close and personal.
Plus, it's been chafing my ass.
以防他单枪匹马摸上来
另外，它一直在磨我的屁股
I don't know what to say.
我不知道该说什么
Let the weapon do the talking.
那就让武器来说吧
Where are you gonna be?
你要去哪？
I'm going high.
我要去高处
- A high hide's never a good idea.
- Who taught you that?
- 藏在高处从来不是个好主意
- 谁告诉你的？
Same person who taught you.
教你的那个人
Well, you're right.
This time, we're doing the ambush.
好吧，你是对的
这次，轮到我们来埋伏了
I still don't know why you're staying in this.
我还是不明白你为什么要待在这里
I told you. I trained Masiello.
I didn't train him to kill Americans.
我告诉过你。我训练过Masiello
我从没教过他杀美国人
What about when you get back to Pendleton?
你什么时候回Pendleton？
You're gonna answer for this.
请你回答
Are you kidding?
你开玩笑吗？
We're not gonna live through this.
我们这次可能活不下去
Lovely view.
视野不错
Totally exposed.
一览无遗
Vehicle coming. Look alive.
有车来了。注意
Wait with the vehicle, Captain Ngoba,
until I make contact with him.
你在车上等，Ngoba上尉，等我和他接触
Yes, Lieutenant.
是，中尉
Beckett?
Beckett!
- Quiet.
- What the fuck are you doing?
- 安静
- 你他妈的在干什么？
- What are you doing here?
- I came to bring you back.
- 你来这干什么？
- 我来带你回去
- Are you crazy?
- Beckett?
- 你疯了吗？
Yes?
怎么？
Who is that young lady looking for?
那个小妞在找谁？
- Me.
- Shame.
- 我
- 真丢人
What is this?
这是什么？
It was supposed to be an ambush,
but you weren't supposed to be here.
这是个埋伏，但是你不应该在这里
Ambush?
Tell me exactly what's going on here.
埋伏？告诉我到底是怎么回事
We got company.
我们有伴了
- Rebels?
- No.
- 叛军？
- 不是
UN 'flag, cute red hats. Doubt they're legit.
联合国徽章，可爱的小红帽
我觉得他们是真的
Anyway, they're taking position
around the perimeter.
不管怎样，他们正在周围抢占位置
I brought soldiers from the base.
那是我从基地带来的士兵
To bring me back.
来带我回去
It's them.
是他们
It's a hit squad.
一个战斗小队
They didn't come with me.
他们不是来帮我的
Why are they shooting at us?
他们为什么要向我们开火？
They're not here to bring me back.
They're here to kill us both.
他们不是来带我回去的
他们要把我们都杀了
Beckett! Give yourself up.
Beckett！放弃抵抗
We have no choice.
我们别无选择
I'll explain later, if we live.
稍后我会解释，如果我们都还活着
Beckett?
You trained us well, no?
Beckett？你把我们练得不错，是不是？
No! They're still stacking up!
不，你们还差得远！
I see you.
我看到你了
- One shot, two kills.
- You heard about that, huh?
- 一箭双雕
- 你见过吗？
- Are you all right?
- Are you kidding?
- 你还好吗？
- 你开什么玩笑？
Lieutenant.
中尉
Ellen. We're ready to move.
Ellen. 我们得转移了
What's the plan?
有什么计划？
Half a dozen uglies out that door, big guy.
门外面有半打丑八怪，大兵
I'll draw their fire.
When I do, you go straight that way.
我会吸引他们的火力
你就直接跑出去
- Okay.
- Make that a dozen. Baker's dozen.
- 好的
- 搞定那一打，十三个
Be careful.
小心
See you back at the base.
基地见
Go, go, go!
Chasing down Ngoba?
要追Ngoba？
Yes.
I got your back, kid.
背后交给我，小子
I am not fighting you.
我不是要对付你
You took us out to that ambush.
你把我们带进了那个陷阱
I am a soldier. I was following orders.
我是个士兵。我要服从命令
Where is he? Masiello!
他在哪？Masiello！
- I don't know.
- Who's behind this?
- 我不知道
- 是谁下的命令？
- He'll kill me.
- I'll kill you! Who?
- 他会杀了我的
- 我会先杀了你！是谁？
I have no proof.
我没有证据
Jäger?
- Colonel Jäger?
- He was using Van Brunt
- Jäger上校？
- 他利用Van Brunt
to funnel American weapons to the rebels.
向叛军偷运美军武器
You knew this? Why didn't you report him?
你知道？为什么你不揭发他？
Who would have believed me? You?
谁会相信我？你？
Would you have believed me?
你曾相信过我吗？
- My men were killed.
- Yours and mine!
- 我的人被杀掉了
- 你的和我的！
And we are next.
然后就是我们
Miller?
Miller, do you read me?
Miller，你听到了吗？
My old instructor is at a loss for words,
baby Beckett.
我的老教练没法说话，小Beckett
Masiello.
That saves introductions.
看起来不用介绍了
Last time we met, I missed you.
上次见面时，我漏掉了你
I'm gonna correct that mistake.
现在我来改正错误
You still with me, baby Beckett?
你在听吗，小Beckett？
Not good enough, Beckett.
还差得远，Beckett
Son of the great Thomas Beckett.
伟大的Thomas Beckett的儿子
It skips a generation, huh?
毕竟差了一代，恩？
Your father wouldn't have missed.
你父亲可不会失手
Let's see how you handle night vision.
让我看看你怎么应付黑暗
What are you dragging this out for?
你还在磨蹭什么？
Well, that wasn't even close.
你偏的够远的
I switched scopes, thanks to you.
多亏了你，我换了望远镜
Won't miss next time.
下次不会失手了
I caught up with Lieutenant Abramowitz
by midday.
中午我追上了Abramowitz中尉
Miller had disappeared.
Miller失踪了
It took most of the next day for us
to get back to the base
我们花了很长时间才回到基地
where I contacted U.S. consulate,
who arranged to bring me back here.
我在那和美国领事馆联系
他们安排我回到这里
In your debriefing,
you said you believed a coalition officer
在你的报告中，你说你确信有联军军官
- was conspiring with the rebels.
- Yes.
- 暗中与叛军勾结
- 是的
And you identified that officer?
你能指认那个官员吗？
Yes.
可以
Sergeant Beckett, do you have any evidence
to corroborate your accusation?
Beckett中士，你有证据可以证明你的指控吗？
No.
没有
I'm afraid without further evidence,
如果没有足够证据
I have no choice but to proceed
with the court-martial.
恐怕我只能继续本次军事法庭审判
What about our men
lying in an unmarked grave in Africa?
在非洲埋在无名墓地中的我的兄弟们怎么办？
What are you gonna do about that?
你打算怎么办？
The U.S. military can do nothing officially.
美军官方对此无能为力
We have rules to obey, regulations to follow.
我们要遵守规章制度
Of course, you don't.
当然，你不需要
Peter? Hans?
I think it's broken.
我想它坏了
Your security detail
won't be coming, Colonel.
你的保安不会来的，上校
You killed them?
你杀了他们？
I don't kill indiscriminately. I'm not you.
我不会随便杀人。我不是你
You must be good.
你一定很优秀
You survived The Italian.
你从‘意大利人’那活下来了
Twice.
两次
He was good.
他很优秀
I was better.
而我更出色
You know how this works, right?
你知道这个怎么用，对吧？
You're here to kill me?
你到这来杀我？
You had my men killed.
你让我的人死了
Ngoba told you that?
Ngoba告诉你的？
Yes.
是的
Well, he's dead.
他死了
Think he would have testified?
你认为他本可以作证？
You're in this picture.
你在这张照片上
Van Brunt had the same one in his house.
Van Brunt的房子里还有一张一样的
You two were friends, weren't you?
你们俩是朋友，是不是？
He helped you sell weapons to our enemies.
他帮你把武器卖给我们的敌人
We sold weapons to both sides.
Congolese government and the rebels.
我们和两边都有生意，刚果政府和叛军
- Why?
- We didn't know who was going to win.
- 为什么？
- 我们不知道谁会赢
We need leverage
with whoever is going to run the country.
不论谁会接管这个国家，都要保证我们的影响力
Is that right?
这么做是对的？
That's the way we have done things
for hundreds of years, Sergeant.
我们几百年来都是这么做的，中士
It's called politics.
这就是政治
Then why kill Van Brunt?
那为什么杀了Van Brunt？
Want me to be honest?
Because he knew too much.
想听真话？因为他知道的太多了
He was the only one
who could connect us to the rebels.
他是我们和叛军之间唯一的联系人
- And my men?
- I'm sorry
- 我的人呢？
- 很遗憾
if your personal loss is more important
to you than the bigger picture of the war.
对你来说个人得失远比战争走向更重要
But you should know,
但你要明白
it looks like the rebels will be forming
the new provisional government,
叛军正打算组建新的临时政府
and because of our policies here,
they will not be hostile to working with us.
而因为我们采取的政策
他们不会反对与我们合作
That's supposed to make it worth it?
这么做值得吗？
I didn't create the situation.
这种局面不是我创造的
But a scandal
will not help us win a global war.
但是闹出丑闻不利于我们赢得全球战争
You've played the game for so long
you forget what we fight for.
你玩这游戏这么久，已经忘记我们为何而战
You know who my father was?
你知道我的父亲是谁吗？
A real soldier, a man who honored
his country with his service,
一个真正的战士，以服务国家为荣
who did his job even when betrayed
by cowards and politicians like you.
即使被懦夫和政治出卖也无怨无悔
Okay, so kill me.
好吧，那就杀了我
Think that will change anything?
你以为这能改变什么？
As long as there's war,
只要还有战争
there will be a necessity for things
most people don't have the stomach for.
让许多人反胃的事就会继续存在
Did you get all that?
你都听到了吗？
Even the sanctimonious part.
包括装圣人的那部分
Colonel Jäger,
Jäger上校
under the United Nations military code
of criminal justice, you are under arrest.
根据联合国军事法规，你被逮捕了
Brandon Beckett?
Major Ed Gulle,
Special Operations Commander.
Ed Gulle少校，特别行动指挥官
I'm not a Marine any more, Major.
我不再是海军陆战队员了，少校
I know. That's why we want to talk to you.
我知道。这正是我来找你的原因
We got a job for you, kid.
我们有工作给你，小子